ANDREW WEBB

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

andrew.webb07@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/andrew-webb07/ https://github.com/andrew-webb07

ABOUT ME

Through a long journey of different jobs and career directions, I finally landed in software development. I am task-oriented and a problem solver so web development has been a great fit. Having just completed the Nashville Software School full-time web development bootcamp, I know I have found a career pursuit with a future and that fits my strengths.

PROJECTS

GIG TAX

Gig-Tax is an application built in React designed to help hire-on musicians keep track of their income and tax deductions in a user-friendly and efficient way. The user is prompted to create an account with a home address and is then able to create and store gigs, tours or receipts. The application then calculates the number of miles traveled to each gig, total of miles, total miles deduction, total amount of money of receipts, gross income total and total tax owed by year for the user. The application uses JavaScript, React, JSX, CSS, JSON server and the Geocoder API from Google.

https://gig-tax.herokuapp.com/login https://github.com/andrew-webb07/gig-tax

PRACTICE PLAN

Practice Plan is an application with the client side built in React and the server side built with Python and Django. It is designed to help musicians and athletes organize their practice routines to grow in excellence more efficiently. The user is prompted to create an account with a practice focus, an option to be public or private and is then able to create and store exercises, practice plans and schedul sessions. The app allows users to view and use public users exercises, exercise categories, and practice plans. The application uses JavaScript, React, JSX, CSS, Python, Django and a SQL database.

https://github.com/andrewwebb07/practice-plan-client

https://github.com/andrewwebb07/practice-plan-server

EXPERIENCE

JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Nashville Software School | Apr 2021 - Sept 2021

NSS is a six-month intensive, full-time software development bootcamp focusing on HTML, CSS, Javascript, React and server-side fundamentals with Python and Django

- Built full-stack browser-based applications using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, Django, SQL and React in both individual and teamwork settings
- Version controlled and collaborated individual and group projects with Git and Github
- Worked in teams using Agile methodology
- · Created comprehensive tests for our code
- Received extensive training on debugging using the debugger in vs code as well as debugging sites using Chrome DevTools
- Deployed projects to AWS, Digital Ocean and Heroku

Group Projects
Rarer - Python, Django,
and React

 $\underline{\text{https://github.com/nss-day-cohort-48/rare-client-wanderering-wizards}}$

https://github.com/nss-day-cohort-48/Rare-API-Django-Wandering-Wizards

- Worked with two others to produce an application that allows users to create posts, categorize those posts, comment on other user's posts as well as tag their own posts
- The app has an admin view that allows an admin to deactivate users as well as edit and delete all user's posts, categories and comments

Giffygram - JavaScript https://github.com/nss-day-cohort-48/giffygram-archies-bunker2-0

- Worked with two others to produce an application that allows users to post gifs, save their favorite gif posts and send other users messages
- Created footer with year dropbox, favorites list checkbox and user dropdown to display selected users posts only

INTEGRATIVE PRODUCTION SOLUTIONS (LABELIVE)

LED Technician and LED Repair Technician | Mar 2019 - Apr 2021 IPS is an integration and production company

- Tested and repaired LED walls, LED panels/pixels and various rigging equipment
- Appointed as head of repairs for LED
- Prepped video orders, truss and lighting displays for tours and events
- On-site video tech on events, shows and festivals around Nashville area with teams
- Drove 20ft box truck and pick-up with trailer for deliveries and pickups

HANDYMAN CONTRACTOR

Carpenter | Oct 2017 - Aug 2019

• Built decks and various other construction projects on houses, churches or businesses

DRIVER (LYFT, UBER, POSTMATES AND SHIPT)

Oct 2017 - Aug 2019

• Drove all over Nashville area to drop off people or deliveries

GUITAR CENTER

Warehouse Manager | Sept 2010 - Aug 2013

Guitar Center is a music-retail company

- Hired, trained and motivated warehouse staff to meet tight schedules and demanding performance targets.
- Learned time management and organization skills with a large task list
- Had responsibility over warehouse and store organization, supply orders, building maintenance, truck shipments, inventory receiving, product shipping, special orders and repairs
- Gained accounting and branch management experience
- Had to count and build cash drawers, manage loss prevention and shrink numbers, organize store, and count and update inventory

EDUCATION

CERTIFICATE OF SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

Nashville Software School | Nashville, TN | 2021

BACHELOR OF ARTS, MAJOR IN MUSIC PERFORMANCE

Forerunner Music Academy | Kansas City, MO | 2013 - 2017

BACHELOR OF ARTS, MAJOR IN COMMUNICATION WITH SPECIALIZATION IN PUBLIC RELATIONS

Michigan State University | East Lansing, MI | 2006 - 2010